atlantic.net 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy

**_Atlantic.Net, Inc. Privacy Policy_**

Atlantic.Net, Inc. (herein referred to as “Atlantic.Net”) values your business, respects your privacy, and is committed to maintaining the integrity and confidentiality of the personal data we collect. The following explains our data compilation methodology as well as the use and management of your private information.  When you visit our website, use our services, or provide your personal information to Atlantic.Net, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy Statement.

**The Information Atlantic.Net Collects**

Atlantic.Net gathers data from its customers and the users (and potential users) of its website and services to help improve content, gather customer interest, behavior and demographic information, to provide targeted information about our company and its products and services, and to enhance user experience. The data we collect comes primarily from you when you visit our website or create an account on our website, purchase a product or service, or engage is customer support activity. The data we collect may include personal information or other data that could identify you individually, such as:

  * Your name
  * Contact information (email address, mailing address, phone number)
  * Payment information (collected, but not stored by Atlantic.Net)
  * IP addresses, Browser details, Device info, Operating System, URL info, etc.
  * Live chat messages
  * Telephone and email conversations
  * Products and services engaged and metrics associated with those services
  * Other personal data that is voluntarily provided 
  * Other third-party profile data available online through our affiliates and partners

Atlantic.Net may use cookies to gather personal information and to utilize analytics software to track and target prospective customers. A cookie is a unique identifier that helps identify website users and tracks their activity. Cookies are not executable code, do not contain viruses, and can be disabled in the web browser’s security settings. Please note, disabling cookies may limit the level of personalization provided during a visit. Atlantic.Net may also monitor usage by tracking which pages on the website are viewed, the number of unique views, as well as time spent on a page.

Atlantic.Net may compile information from third-party providers (including Atlantic.Net affiliates located in the European Union and the UK), such as site redirects, search engine queries, and SEO tools. We may also make use of publicly available data such as names, email addresses, and mailing addresses. Furthermore, our advertisements may use tracking technology to determine the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. 

Atlantic.Net does not market or provide services, or knowingly collect any information, from children under the age of 16 in accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

**How Atlantic.Net Uses Information Collected**

Atlantic.Net may use personal information in the following ways:

  * To personalize your web experience based on your individual needs and patterns.
  * To deliver and maintain our Products and Services.
  * To improve our website and service offerings based on your feedback.
  * To improve customer service and the delivery of support.
  * To process transactions.
  * To facilitate marketing analytics, such as A/B Testing.
  * To communicate with you via email. The email address provided may be used periodically to process orders, provide notifications of new or updated products and services, provide billing notifications, share newsletters, announce promotions, or warn of system maintenance.
  * To communicate important information to you via mail, web or telephone.
  * To prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our Website.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

Atlantic.Net does not sell, trade, or transfer personal information to any unrelated entities, with the exception of trusted third parties who perform functions on our behalf. We may be required to disclose information in compliance with court orders, subpoenas, summons, discovery requests, warrants, statutes, regulations or governmental request or to enforce our legal rights and protect the rights and safety of others. We assume no obligation to inform users if such information is requested.

**Lawfulness of Processing**

Atlantic.Net makes every effort to conform to all applicable laws and regulations when collecting and using the personal information described above.  Our methods of collection and use are determined by the types of data collected and the particular context in which we collect it. We will primarily collect and use personal information when we are entering into an agreement to provide products and services to you and we need that data for the performance of our agreement. By entering into such an agreement with us and by agreeing to our privacy policy, you are providing consent to use your information as necessary. We will also collect information when you have provided specific consent to receive certain types of communication from us (newsletters, product/service announcements, promotions, etc.) or to customize your experience on our website.

**Privacy Shield Policy for the EU and/or Switzerland**

Atlantic.Net, Inc. complies with the EU-US and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Atlantic.Net adheres to the Privacy Shield principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce site at [https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)

**Opt-In / Opt-Out, Access, and Right-to-be-Forgotten Procedures**

You may be requested to Opt-In to specific types of processing when providing personal information to Atlantic.Net. This procedure verifies that you understand and consent to our collecting and using your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy as well as any applicable governmental regulations. Please understand that by not Opting-In there may be some products and services that may be unavailable to you.

You may Opt-Out after having chosen to receive certain types of communication from us, if they are not related to the performance of a service agreement.  At your request, we will discontinue such communication. If you wish to opt out, please notify us at [opt-out@atlantic.net](mailto:opt-out@atlantic.net) or write us at Business Development; Atlantic.Net, Inc.; 440 West Kennedy Blvd.; Suite 3; Orlando, FL 32810.  Please note that it may take up to 10 days to process your request. Due to the nature of our Service Level Agreement (SLA), you cannot opt out of Service and Maintenance Notifications.

Atlantic.Net recognizes that citizens in the EU and other designated countries may request access to the personal information we maintain about them, under the GDPR. Under certain circumstances, Atlantic.Net will provide an individual access to their Personal Information and will allow the individual to correct, amend or delete inaccurate data. Atlantic.Net will also allow an individual to limit the use or disclosure of their personal data, according to applicable law. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete data, or who seeks to limit the use or disclosure of personal data should direct his query to [opt-out@atlantic.net](mailto:opt-out@atlantic.net) or write us at the address detailed above. If requested to remove or limit the use of data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

**Scope of Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy applies to information collected through our website, but may also apply to other collected information as required by law.

**SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**

Atlantic.Net is committed to take reasonable security measures to protect the confidentiality of the information in our possession. To that end, we utilize technologies and measures designed to protect information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information. 

Databases with personal information are accessible only by Atlantic.Net employees who are bound by a confidentiality and nondisclosure agreement.

**Server Data**

Atlantic.Net provides services that include acting as an Internet Service Provider, a Colocation Services Provider, a Managed Services Provider, and a Cloud Services Provider to customers. When providing these services, we do not determine the purposes and/or means of processing any private data that our customers may store or transmit via those services. When providing these services, Atlantic.Net is acting only as a channel for data owned and handled by third parties. Each individual Atlantic.Net customer determines the sensitivity of their data, identifies the appropriate methods to secure and protect that data, and may request Atlantic.Net to assist, when applicable, in protecting that data.

Atlantic.Net ** ** does not store customer passwords or private SSH keys and has no access to customers’ server data.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

Atlantic.Net reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time and without notice to customers or the public. This Privacy Policy was last updated as of May 25, 2018.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact us:

Atlantic.Net, Inc.  
440 West Kennedy Blvd.  
Suite 3  
Orlando, FL 32810
